<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guides on Bothell Urbanism Guide</title><link>https://bothell.urbanism-guide.com/pr-preview/3/guides/</link><description>Recent content in Guides on Bothell Urbanism Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bothell.urbanism-guide.com/pr-preview/3/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Downtown Revitalization</title><link>https://bothell.urbanism-guide.com/pr-preview/3/guides/downtown-revitalization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bothell.urbanism-guide.com/pr-preview/3/guides/downtown-revitalization/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="downtown-revitalization-in-bothell">Downtown Revitalization in Bothell&lt;a class="anchor" href="#downtown-revitalization-in-bothell">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bothell&amp;rsquo;s downtown transformation is one of the Puget Sound region&amp;rsquo;s most ambitious suburban-to-urban revitalization stories. Beginning in 2010, the city invested over &lt;a href="https://www.bothellwa.gov/323/Downtown-Subarea-Plan-Regulations">$150 million in public infrastructure&lt;/a> to move a state highway, rebuild its Main Street, and create the conditions for a walkable mixed-use center where strip malls and auto-oriented businesses once stood.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-downtown-looks-like-today">What downtown looks like today&lt;a class="anchor" href="#what-downtown-looks-like-today">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Downtown Bothell today bears little resemblance to what it looked like in the mid-2000s. Where SR 522 once bisected the city center, a &lt;a href="https://www.bothellwa.gov/1306/Main-Street-Enhancement-Project-Facts">curbless Main Street&lt;/a> now hosts outdoor dining, movable bollards, and flex zones that can close to traffic for community events. Mixed-use buildings line Bothell Way NE, bringing over 1,000 housing units and ground-floor retail to what was previously low-density commercial land.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bike Network</title><link>https://bothell.urbanism-guide.com/pr-preview/3/guides/bike-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bothell.urbanism-guide.com/pr-preview/3/guides/bike-network/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bike-network-in-bothell">Bike Network in Bothell&lt;a class="anchor" href="#bike-network-in-bothell">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bothell sits at the crossroads of some of the Puget Sound region&amp;rsquo;s most important regional trails, yet its on-street bike infrastructure has historically lagged behind. The city adopted a &lt;a href="https://www.bothellwa.gov/1415/Bike-Plan">Citywide Bike Plan&lt;/a> in April 2023, acknowledging its transition from &amp;ldquo;a predominantly motorized vehicle-only suburban community to a multimodal community&amp;rdquo; and laying out a long-term vision for protected bike facilities connecting neighborhoods to trails, transit, and destinations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="regional-trails">Regional trails&lt;a class="anchor" href="#regional-trails">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Three major regional trails pass through Bothell, forming the backbone of the city&amp;rsquo;s bike network. All three are paved, shared-use paths separated from motor vehicle traffic.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>